Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight papers
1945-1995 (bulk 1973-1994)
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Lawrence, Jacob
9 linear feet
The papers of African American painter and teacher Jacob Lawrence and his wife Gwendolyn Knight measure 9 linear feet and date from 1945 to 1995, with the bulk of the material dated 1973-1994. More than half of the collection is correspondence with friends, artists, students, school children, art schools, galleries, museums, and others. Also found are writings by Lawrence and others, newsclippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, press releases, brochures, books, photographs of Lawrence, Knight, and Lawrence's artwork, scattered financial and business records, and two small lithographs by James Rosenquist.
Biographical Note
Modernist painter and educator Jacob Lawrence (1917-2000) was born in 1917 as Jacob Armstead Lawrence in Atlantic City, New Jersey. He began his art studies at the Utopia Children’s Center in New York City’s Harlem district where he studied under the painter Charles Alston. Lawrence dropped out of high school at the age of sixteen to continue his art instruction with Alston but this time at the Harlem Art Workshop where he met several artists associated with the Harlem Renaissance including the sculptor Augusta Savage.
Gwendolyn Knight (b.1913) was born in Barbados and moved to New York City with her adoptive parents when she was seven. She attended New York’s Wadleigh High School and later Howard University in Washington, D. C. where she studied fine arts with Lois Mailou Jones and James Porter. Forced to leave her studies at Howard because of the Depression, Knight returned to Harlem and continued her artistic pursuits in Augusta Savage’s workshop. In1935, Knight joined the Harlem Mural Project of the Works Progress Administration (WPA) working under Selma Day and Charles Alston. Lawrence and Knight met in Savage’s workshop and married in the summer of 1941.
During the Depression, Lawrence also joined the WPA Federal Arts Project in Harlem. Finding WPA murals overwhelming, Lawrence concentrated on traditional painting instead. He produced his first major works in the late 1930s, most notably the Toussaint L’Ouverture series, images that document the life of the revolutionary hero and Haiti’s struggle for independence. Other significant works include visual narratives of the lives of abolitionists Harriet Tubman and Frederick Douglass. In 1940, Lawrence received the prestigious Julius Rosenwald Fellowship making it possible to purchase his first art studio on 125th Street in the heart of Harlem. He soon portrayed Harlem street life in paintings that became commentaries on the role of African Americans in United States society with highly developed themes of resistance and social opposition. That same year, Lawrence began his most celebrated series, “The Migration of the American Negro,” multiple tempera panels depicting the exodus of African American sharecroppers in the south to northern industrial cities in search of better employment and social opportunities. Edith Halpert exhibited the works in their entirety at her Downtown Gallery in 1941 establishing Lawrence as the first African American artist to exhibit in a top New York gallery. The following year, New York’s Museum of Modern Art and the Phillips Collection in Washington, DC each bought half of the sixty panels in the series, helping to further Lawrence’s career within the larger world of American art.
In the summer of 1946, the artist Joseph Albers invited Lawrence to teach at North Carolina’s Black Mountain College. It was the first in a series of teaching positions in prestigious art schools including Pratt Institute (1956-1971), Brandeis University (1965), The New School (1966), the Art Students League (1967), and others. During the 1950s and 1960s, Lawrence’s work continued to focus on racism and political activism but in the late 1960s shifted to themes of racial harmony.
Both Lawrence and Knight continued independent careers in art. Knight pursued her art studies at the New School in New York and the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture in Maine. In the mid-1960s, she collaborated with other female artists to form the Studio Gallery in New York City. Knight's main body of work consists of portraits and still-lifes that incorporate expressions of African sculpture, Impressionism, dance and theater. Focusing on gesture, her art is described as light and airy with a minimum of lines allowing empty space to define the work.
In 1970, Lawrence traveled to Seattle to teach as a visiting artist at the University of Washington. He was hired on a permanent basis the following year and remained on staff until his retirement in 1986. Jacob Lawrence died June 9, 2000, in Seattle, Washington at the age of 83. Gwendolyn Knight continues to live and paint in Seattle and actively exhibits her work around the country.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of African American painter and teacher Jacob Lawrence and his wife Gwendolyn Knight measure 9 linear feet and date from 1945 to 1995, with the bulk of the material dated 1973-1994. More than half of the collection is correspondence with friends, artists, students, school children, art schools, galleries, museums, and others. Also found are writings by Lawrence and others, newsclippings, exhibition catalogs and announcements, press releases, brochures, books, photographs of Lawrence, Knight, and Lawrence's artwork, and two small lithographs by James Rosenquist. Scattered business and financial files primarily document Lawrence's relationship with the Terry Dintenfass Gallery in New York.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1951, circa 1967-1995(Box 1, OV 10; 4 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1952, circa 1962-1995 (Box 1-5; 4.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings and Lists, circa 1973-1995 (Box 5-6; 6 folders)
Series 4: Printed Material, circa 1945-1995 (Box 6-9; 3.8 linear feet)
Series 5: Photographs, circa 1986-1991 (Box 9, OV 10; 3 folders)
Series 6: Financial and Business Files, 1962-1992 (Box 9; 7 folders)
Series 7: Original Artwork, 1984, undated (Box 9; 1 folder)
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following index terms. People, families and organizations are listed under "Names" when they are creators or contributors and under "Subjects" when they are the topic of collection contents.
Subjects-Topical:
Painting, Modern -- 20th century -- United States; African American artists -- New York (State) -- New York; African American artists -- Washington (State) -- Seattle; Painters -- New York (State); Painters -- Washington (State)
Types of Materials:
Photographs
Names:
Bearden, Romare, 1911-1988; Bocour, Leonard, 1910-; Dintenfass, Terry, 1920-; Eichenberg, Fritz, 1901-; Evergood, Philip, 1901-1973; Halpert, Edith Gregor, 1900-1970; Knight, Gwendolyn
Provenance
Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight donated their papers to the Archives of American Art in five accretions between 1979 and 1997.
Separated Material
Additional scattered materials loaned by Jacob Lawrence in 1966 were microfilmed by the Archives of American Art on reel D286.
Related Material
Jacob Lawrence papers are available at the Syracuse University Library, Special Collections Department and were loaned to the Archives of American Art in 1993 for microfilming on reels 4571-4573.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of the collection was digitized in 2007 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website. Materials which have not been scanned include books, miscellaneous printed material, and photographs of artwork.
Restrictions on Access
The collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website. Photographs and slides of artwork have not been scanned.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1951, circa 1967-1995, Series 1:; (Box 1, OV 10; 4 folders)
  This series includes awards, certificates, curriculum vitae, and other material including several appointment books and a program for a memorial service held for Mrs. Rosa Armstead Lawrence in 1951.
  - Appointment Books, 1967-1969, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Awards, Certificates, Curriculum Vitae, Ephemera, 1984-1995, undated, (See also OV 10) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Program, Memorial Service, 1951, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Awards and Certificates, 1984-1995, (See also box 1, folder 3) (Box OV 10)
- Correspondence, 1952, circa 1961-1995, Series 2:; (Box 1-5; 4.5 linear feet)
  This series contains extensive general correspondence, including postcards and greeting cards, with friends, artists, elementary school children, university students, government agencies, art schools, galleries, museums, publishing houses, and others. Correspondence includes letters from Charles Alston, Romare Bearden, and Langston Hughes, among other important individuals. Also found are interesting letters from Jacob Lawrence’s nephew, Terry Coles, and niece, Judy Payne. Found among the correspondence are occasional requests for letters of recommendation from former students with photographic slides or other reproductions of artwork as attachments. Also found as attachments with other letters are newspaper clippings, newsletters, and photographs. Topics discussed include upcoming exhibitions, book projects, commissions, speaking engagements, and award ceremonies. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by individual or organization name.
  - Alain Locke Society, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ALJIRA Center for Contemporary Art, Newark, NJ, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alston, Charles, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alston, Peg, 1976-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, New York, NY, 1982-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amistad Research Center, New Orleans, LA, 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Arizona State University, 1975-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, Chicago, IL, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Artists Equity Association, Inc., 1974-1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Art Museum Missoula, Missoula, MT, 1995, (Partially scanned) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Baltimore Museum of Art, Baltimore, MD, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Barnett, Arthur and Virginia, 1982-1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bearden, Romare, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bellevue Art Museum, Bellevue, WA, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Berman, Avis, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bikel, Theodore, 1978, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Black Nation, (Amiri Baraka), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Black Scholar, 1977-1978, 1980, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bloomfield College, Bloomfield, NJ, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bocour Artist Colors, Inc., 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Brandywine Workshop, 1975-1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Brockman Gallery, Los Angeles, CA, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brooklyn Museum, Brooklyn, NY, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Burd, Geoffrey, 1991-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - B, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - California Museum of Afro-American History and Culture, Los Angeles, CA, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Champ, Norman B., Jr., undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Chicago Historical Society, 1990, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Christofides, Koren, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Cincinnati Art Museum, Cincinnati, OH, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - City University of New York, 1973-1995 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Clark, Claude, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Clark, Kenneth, 1976-1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Coates, Helena and Edwin, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Cohen, Brian, 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Colby College, Maine, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Coles, Terry, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Connie Goldman Productions, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Container Corporation of America, Chicago, IL, 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Cooper, David B., 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cox, Joseph Mason Andrew, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - C, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - DeBrew, John S., Jr., 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - DeCaro, Pat, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Denver Art Museum, Denver, CO, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Detroit Institute of Arts, Detroit, MI, 1974-1993 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Dinwiddie Middle School, Dinwiddie, VA, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - District 1199 Cultural Center Inc., New York, NY, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - D, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Emanuel Pieterson Historical Society, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Evans, Walter O., 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Evergreen Galleries, Olympia, WA, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - E, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Factory of Visual Arts, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fans, 1973-1995, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-4)
  - First Names, 1973-1995, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Fisk University, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Francine Seders Gallery Ltd., Seattle, WA, 1982-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Freedomways, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - F, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Galleries/Museums, Miscellaneous 1973-1995, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
  - Gallery Two Nine One, Atlanta, GA, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gay, Nena, 1980-1983, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Georgetown Elementary School, Columbus, GA, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Golberg, Peggy, 1977, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Golden, Judith, 1974-1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Gordon Bibb Elementary School, Decatur, AL, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Greene, Carroll, Jr., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Grigsby, Eugene, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gwathmey, Rosalie, 1986-1987, 1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - G, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hafermehl, Louis and Frances, 1974-1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Hampton University Museum, Hampton, VA, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Harlem School of the Arts, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Harper Collins Publishers, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Harris, Michael, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1971-1986 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hawthorne Elementary School, Seattle, WA, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hazzard, Bill and Ellen, 1981-1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Henry Art Gallery, Seattle, WA, 1969-1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - High Museum of Art, Atlanta, GA, 1986, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Historical Society of Seattle and King County, Seattle, WA, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Holiday House, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Howard University, Washington, DC, 1972-1985, 1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Hunter Museum of Art, Chattanooga, TN, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - H, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ives-Sillman Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - I, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Joslyn Art Museum, Omaha, NE, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - J, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Katonah Museum of Art, Katonah, NY, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kayden, Herbert and Gabrielle Reem, 1972-1988, 1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - KCTSeattle 9, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Kebede, Alitash, 1982-1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Keeter, Susan, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Knight, Miriam, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Kushner, Marilyn, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - K, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Lamb, Bob, 1985-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Lewis, Samella, 1974-1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Links, Inc., 1984, 1990, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Local 535 Service Employees International Union, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles, CA, 1972, 1992-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lowden Elementary School, Highland Hgts., OH, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Lowenthal, Edith and Milton, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - L, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - McIntosh Gallery, Atlanta, GA, 1987-1995 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - McColl, Sue, 1980-1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Majors, Susan (Steadman) and Bill, 1979-1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Maple Hills Elementary School, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Maryland Institute, College of Art, 1979-1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Memorial Art Gallery, University of Rochester, Rochester, NY, 1981-1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, NY, 1982-1993 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Midtown Payson Galleries, Inc., New York, NY, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Milwaukee Art Museum, Milwaukee, WI, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Monroe Middle School, Rochester, NY, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Montclair Art Museum, Montclair, NJ, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Museum of African American Art, Los Angeles, CA, 1981-1995 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Museum of Fine Arts Houston, Houston, TX, 1992-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York, NY, 1943, 1970-1979, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - M, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - National Academy of Design, New York, NY, 1972-1993 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - National Art Education Association, 1971-1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, (NAACP), 1979-1995 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - National Center of Afro-American Artists, Inc., Roxbury, MA, 1978-1990 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - National Conference of Artists, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1979-1990 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, DC, 1985-1995 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - National Urban League, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - New Deal Films (Mary Lance), 1979-1990 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - New Jersey State Museum, Trenton, NJ, 1979-1991 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - New Orleans Museum of Art, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - New York Public Library/Schomberg Center for Research in Black Culture, 1985-1993 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - New York University, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Nguzo Saba Films, Inc., San Francisco, CA, 1980-1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - North Beach School, Seattle, WA, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - North Carolina Museum of Art, Raleigh, NC, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - N, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Oakland Museum, Oakland, CA, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Orens Elementary School., Baltimore, MD, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - O, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Pacific Northwest Magazine, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Parker, James T., Jr., 1983-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Patterson, Raymond, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Paulson, Don, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Payne, Judy and Duval and Michelle, 1980-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Peshine Ave. School, South Orange, NJ, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, Philadelphia, PA, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Phillips Collection, Washington, DC, 1966, 1979,1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Portland Museum of Art, Portland, OR, 1979, 1984-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pratt Institute, Brooklyn, NY, 1961, 1967-1979, 1984-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Publishers, Miscellaneous, 1973-1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Puget Sound Primary School, Seattle, WA, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - P, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Reynolds House, American Art, Winston-Salem, NC, 1980-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Richards, Lorna, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Rizzoli International Publications, Inc., 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Rosenblum, Paula, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1978, 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - St. Ann School, New York, NY, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - St. Louis Art Museum, St. Louis, MO, 1974-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - St. Mary’s Academy, Norfolk, VA, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sand Hill Elementary School, Atlanta, GA, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Seattle Art Museum, Seattle, WA, 1973-1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Seattle Arts Commission, Seattle, WA, 1974-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Seattle Children’s Theater, Seattle, WA, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Seattle Urban League, 1981-1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Seeger, Pete, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Silver Lake Elementary School, Mill Creek, WA, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Simon and Schuster, New York, NY, 1972, 1980, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Skinner, Carlton and Solange, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, Skowhegan, ME, 1972-1974, 1980-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Smith, Charles and Elie, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Smith, Vincent, 1978-1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1972-1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Spellman College, Atlanta, GA, 1977-1978, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Spradling, Grant, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - State of Washington, 1973-1990 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - State University of New York (Albany, Binghamton, Purchase), 1984, 1988, 1990, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Stevens Elementary School, Seattle, WA, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Stevens, May, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Students, Former, 1973-1995, (see also OV 10, Oversized illustrated letter from Reiko Yamaguchi) (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Students/Schools, General, 1973-1995, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
  - Studio Museum in Harlem, New York, NY, 1975-1986 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Sunnycrest Elementary School, 1986, (Partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Syracuse Cultural Workers, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Syracuse University, 1979, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - S, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tacoma Art Museum, Tacoma, WA, 1990-1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Terry Dintenfass, Inc., 1964-1992, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Toledo Museum of Art, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Transworld Art Corporation, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Troster, Singer and Co., 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - T, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - United States Information Service/Agency Washington, DC, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - University of Minnesota, Twin Cities, University Art Museum, Minneapolis, MN, 1978-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - University of Missouri, Kansas, City, 1974-1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - University of Washington, Seattle, WA, 1969-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - U, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vermont Studio Center, 1990-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - V, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Wantu Animation, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Washington Bar Association, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Washington State Capital Museum, 1979-1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Weaver, Michael S., 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - West Collection, Art and the Law, St. Paul, MN, 1983-1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Wheat, Ellen, 1982-1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - White House, Washington, DC, 1980-1981, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, NY, 1972-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Who’s Who in American Art, Chicago, IL, 1972-1991 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Kansas City, MO, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Workshop, Inc., 1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - W, Miscellaneous, circa 1973-1995 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Yale University, New Haven, CT, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Y, Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Z, Miscellaneous, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Illustrated Letter by Artist Reiko Yamaguchi, undated, (See also box 4, folder 38) (Box OV 10)